Inventory of the Francis P. Lee Papers 1727-1866
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Francis P. Lee Papers, 1727-1866.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 65 L51
600 items.
Papers of Francis Prioleau Lee, his wife Sarah Ann (Cooper) Lee, and her family.
Francis Prioleau Lee,; Sarah Ann Cooper Lee.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
In the possession of Swem Library in 1966.
Biographical/Historical Information
Francis Prioleau Lee (1810-1847) was an Episcopal minister who served churches in Camden, New Jersey; Tallahassee, Florida; Camden, South Carolina; and Mobile, Alabama. He married Sarah Ann (Cooper) Lee.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1727-1866, of Francis Prioleau Lee, his wife Sara Ann (Cooper) Lee, and her family. Chiefly papers, 1830-1850, of Francis P. Lee and concerning his estate. The papers reflect his education at Princeton University and at the General Theological Seminary, New York, New York. They cover his career as an Episcopal minister serving churches in Camden, New Jersey; Tallahassee, Florida; Camden, South Carolina; and Mobile, Alabama (Christ Church); and his trying to obtain an appointment to the faculty of the College of South Carolina. A major portion of the papers consist of manuscript sermons by Lee.
The collection also includes wills and estate papers of Joseph Cooper and Benjamin Cooper; correspondence concerning lands in New Jersey and Pennsylvania inherited from Benjamin B. Cooper; and the financial problems of Sarah Ann (Cooper) Lee's brother, Ralph V. M. Cooper.
Arrangement
Organization
The collection is divided into two series. The first series is primarily correspondence, with some legal documents and other papers included. The second series is Lee's sermons.
Arrangement
Each series is arranged chronologically. Manuscript volumes and undated letters are located at the end of the correspondence series.
Additional Bibliography
Bibliography
A published copy of Francis P. Lee's manuscript speech in Box 4, folder 3, is in the Rare Books Department with call number 806 L511.
Lee, Francis Prioleau. A Lecture on the Advantages of Associations for Literary Purposes delivered...February 3, 1843. Camden, S.C.: Printed for the Lyceum by T. W. Pegues, 1843.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Cooper family.
Persons:
Lee, Francis Prioleau, 1810- 1847.; Lee, Sarah Ann Cooper, fl. 1835- 1859.; Cooper, Benjamin B., d. ca. 1835.; Cooper, Ralph V. M., fl. 1835-1852.; Cooper, Joseph, d. 1727.; Cooper, Benjamin, d. 1772.
Subjects:
University of South Carolina-- History.; Episcopal Church-- Clergy.; Episcopal Church--History--19th century.; Sermons, American--19th century.
Contents List
  Series 1: Correspondence and Legal Papers
- Correspondence and Legal Papers.
  - Last will and testament of Joseph Cooper of Newton, New Jersey, October 2, 1727., 5 pages. D. Cop. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Lease granted by Benjamin Cooper to "his son, William Cooper, March 9, 1768., 3 pages. ADS. (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Will of Benjamin Cooper, of Gloucester County, New Jersey, August 1, 1772., 1 item. D. Cop. (Folder 1:3)
    In favour of his wife Elizabeth, his sons Samuel, Joseph, James, and William, and his daughter Lydia.
  - Probate document for will of Benjamin Cooper, October 9, 1772., 1 page. PD. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Deed of Elizabeth Cooper to William Cooper, October 10, 1784., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 1:4)
    Deed renouncing various rents assigned to Elizabeth Cooper by her deceased husband, Benjamin Cooper, in favour of her son William.
  - Poem by Francis P. L[ee] "To Miss Caroline Carmichael," October 28, 1830., 1 page. Ms. (Box-folder 1:5)
    On reverse of leaf, poem by Francis P. Lee "To Miss Louisa, on the eve of her departure from Morristown." 1 page. Ms.
  - C. A. Boykin, Camden, to Francis P. Lee, Princeton, New Jersey, March 30, 1831., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:6)
    Family news.
  - Poem written by Francis P. Lee for the Album of William Elmer, December 1831., 2 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Copy? of a satire written at Princeton, December 1831., 2 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Satire written at Princeton, January 1832., 2 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 1:9)
    Mentions F. P. Lee.
  - [Francis P. Lee], Nassau Hall [Princeton], to his mother, April 1, 1832., 2 pages. AL. Cop. (Box-folder 1:10)
    Has converted to Christianity.
  - [Francis P. Lee], Orange, to J. A. Boykin, June 2, 1832., 4 pages. AL. Cop. (Box-folder 1:11)
    Discusses his religious conversion.
  - [Francis P. Lee?], n.p., to Mrs. Elizabeth H. Ryan, Charlestown, South Carolina, [ca. 1832]., 4 pages. AL. Fragment. (Box-folder 1:11a)
    Discusses his conversion; plans to enter Columbia College or the Seminary; tells steps New Y[ork City] has taken to avoid cholera; tariff bill passed; asks about friends.
  - N. B. Holmes, New York, to Mrs. Francis Lee, Camden, South Carolina, June 5, 1833., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:12)
    Francis in poor health; Holmes feels a trip home could be injurious to his health.
  - Francis P. Lee, General Theological Seminary, to W. R. Whittingham, March 19, 1834., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 1:13)
    Will join his parish.
  - W. R. Whittingham, to Francis P. Lee, Theological Seminary, March 21, 1834., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Charles C. Gaskell, Cooper's Point, to "cousin", April 6, 1834., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:15)
    Encloses check for $1700.
  - B. Holmes, Orange, to Francis P. Lee, Theological Seminary, New York, May 12, 1834., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:16)
    Enjoyed his visit and invites him to visit again; does not want to become involved with slavery; does not think political temperance will accomplish anything.
  - F[rancis] P. Lee, Theological Seminary, to his mother, Mrs. Francis Lee, May 15, 1834., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:17)
    Wants to travel to Europe.
  - N. B. Holmes to Francis P. Lee, Ulster County, New York, July 26, 1834., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:18)
    Hopes he is well.
  - B. Holmes, Orange, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, September 14, 1834., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:19)
    Talks of religious matters.
  - Description of land in McKean, Venango, Jefferson, and Indiana counties, Pennsylvania, held in trust by Benjamin B. Cooper for the children of Sarah Cooper deceased, December 4, 1834., 4 pages. AD. (Box-folder 1:20)
  - H. D. M[andeville], Jr., Philadelphia, to Francis P. Lee, Gen[eral] Theolog[ical] Seminary, New York, December 21, 1834., 3 pages. ALS (Box-folder 1:21)
    Laments Nevitt's death; his father is bankrupt.
  - Francis P. Lee, New York, to H.D. Mandeville, January 5, 1835., 3 pages. ALS. Cop. (Box-folder 1:22)
    Thanks him for books; laments death of a friend, G. W. Nevitt. Includes Francis P. Lee to the father of G. W. Nevitt. Laments the death of his friend. Also includes Francis P. Lee to G. P. McCullogh. Tells of Nevitt's death.
  - Indenture between Sarah Ann Cooper and Jacob and Joel Sigar, March 7, 1835., 2 pages. DS. (Box-folder 1:23)
    Rents land in Gloucester County, New Jersey, from Sarah Ann Cooper.
  - W. R. Whittingham, Carquienanne, to Francis P. Lee, Prot[estant] Episc[opal] Theolog[ica]l Seminary, New York, USA, March 9, 1835., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:24)
    Urges him to visit Europe; discusses religion.
  - Constitution of Christ Church, Mobile, and proposed amended constitution of Christ Church, Mobile, March 22, 1835., 2 pages. PD. (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Power of attorney from Ralph V. M. Cooper, April 8, 1835., 1 page. D. Cop. (Box-folder 1:26)
    Gives power of attorney to Charles C. Gaskell to sell land from B. B. Cooper estate.
  - Note payable--$3000 by Ralph V. M. Cooper, March 8, 1837., 2 pages. PD. (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Note payable--$2800 signed by Ralph V. M. Cooper and Sarah Ann Cooper, October 2, 1837., 2 pages. DS. (Box-folder 1:28)
  - Document in case of creditors v. Cooper estate, [1838?], 3 pages. D. (Box-folder 1:29)
  - List of settlement of B. B. Cooper estate, 1838-1845., 3 pages. D. (Box-folder 1:30)
  - Ralph V. M. Cooper, Coopers Creek, to Frank [Francis P. Lee], Camden, South Carolina, January 18, 1838., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:31)
    Describes his finances.
  - Charles C. Gaskell, Rose Cottage, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, April 27, 1838., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:32)
    Will send the bonds and deed from Ralph [V. M. Cooper].
  - Francis P. Lee, Tarrytown [New York], to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, May 30, 1838?, 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:33)
    Went to the boat and saw Washington Irving who invited him to come visit; hopes she is well.
  - Tho[ma]s B. Lee, New Orleans, to Brother [Francis P. Lee], August 20, 1838., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:34)
    Has received the boxes; has been sick; wants to visit mother; there is no position as bookkeeper for James Stuart.
  - F[rancis P.] Lee to mother, Frances Lee, September 2, 1838., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:34)
    Ben's accounts are too high; the town is healthy despite whooping cough elsewhere; is glad she has met some of his friends.
    (On same leaf as Thomas B. Lee to Francis P. Lee, August 20, 1838.)
  - R. V. M. Cooper, Cape May C.H., to Francis P. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, September 4, 1838., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:35)
    Francis P. Lee will be sued; discusses his financial problems.
  - Tho[ma]s Eston Randolph, et al., Tallahassee, to [Fra]ncis P. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, October 10, 1838., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:36)
    Vestry invites him to become their pastor.
  - Francis P. Lee, to Mrs. Lee, [November, 1838]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:37)
    Went to the ship again.
  - Francis P. Lee, Astor House, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, [November 15, 1838]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:38)
    Hopes to sail soon.
  - Francis P. Lee, New York, to Brethren, November 16, [1838]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:39)
    Expresses regret at leaving his old congregation.
  - Francis P. Lee, New York, to Mrs. Francis P. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, [November 18, 1838.], 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:40)
    Will preach in New York.
  - Francis P. Lee, New York, to Mrs. S[arah] C. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, [November 18, 1838], 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:41)
    Has not yet sailed; is staying with Mr. Higbee.
  - Charles C. Gaskell, Rose Cottage, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, November 20, [1838]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:42)
    Describes legal problems with McKean [County, Pennsylvania] lands; encloses copy of judge's letter.
  - Francis P. Lee, New York, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, November 21, [1838]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:43)
    Waiting for the boat to sail to Tallahassee.
  - Francis P. Lee, New York, to Mrs. Sarah C. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, November 23, 1838., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:44)
    Will sail for Florida.
  - F[rancis] P. Lee, Tallahassee, to Mrs. Sarah C. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, December 22, 1838., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:45)
    The church is pretty; describes local church activities.
  - F[rancis] P. Lee, Tallahassee, Florida, to Mrs. Francis P. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, January 3, 1839., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:46)
    Describes the area.
  - F[rancis] P. Lee, [Tallahassee, Florida], to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, [January 10, 1838]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:47)
    Sends her a forget-me-not; good weather; describes his new congregation.
  - Tho[ma]s B. Lee, New Orleans, to Frank [Francis P. Lee], January 29, 1839., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:48)
    Glad Francis P. Lee moved to Florida; asks if any local merchants could be sent a consignment; asks him to visit.
  - John Wright, Philadelphia, to Mrs. Francis P. Lee, Camden, New Jersey, February 7, 1839., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:49)
    Wants payment on a Ralph V. M. Cooper note.
  - Tho[ma]s B. Lee, New Orleans, to Frank [Francis P. Lee], April 16, 1839., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:50)
    Letter of introduction for W. Sully.
  - [Francis P. Lee], Springfield, Massachusetts, to Mrs. Francis P. Lee, New Brunswick, New Jersey, August 22, 1839., 4 pages. AL. Fragment. (Box-folder 1:51)
    Describes his trip.
  - Geo[rge] P. MacCullock, Morristown, October 23, 1839., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 1:52)
    Letter of recommendation for Fr[ancis] P. Lee.
  - W. R. Whittingham, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, So. Carolina, October 26, 1839., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:53)
    Letter of recommendation for Francis P. Lee.
  - Ed G. Higbee, New York, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, October 28, 1839., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:54)
    Letter of recommendation.
  - Benj[amin] T. Anderson, October 30, 1839., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 1:55)
  - Gab. H. Ford, Morristown, New Jersey, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, November 11, 1839., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:56)
  - G. W. Doane, November 18, 1839., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 1:57)
  - Henry Jas. Anderson, Columbia Coll[ege], New York, to [Francis P. Lee], November 18, 1839., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:58)
  - Ralph V. M. Cooper, New Orleans, to Francis P. Lee, Tallahassee, Florida, January 1, 1840., 4 pages. ALS. Fragment. (Box-folder 1:59)
    Describes his trip by boat from Philadelphia and trouble with sailors; has been offered another chance to go to sea.
  - Sarah [Lee], Pearl Street, to Francis P. Lee, Tallahassee, Florida, February 1, 1840., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:60)
    Visiting her grandmother; laments Ben's death.
  - H. R. Cleveland, Boston, to Francis P. Lee, Tallahassee, Florida, March 23, 1840., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:61)
    Regrets not writing sooner; discusses the bishop; sorry Francis P. Lee did not get the professorship [at College of South Carolina]; describes his life in Boston.
  - Francis P. Lee, Charleston, South Carolina, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, April 4, 1840., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:62)
    Has prepared an article for publication; will travel to Savannah; describes his trip.
  - F[rancis] P. L[ee], Cumberland on the Potomac, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, June 4, 1840., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:63)
    Will travel to Philadelphia; describes his travels.
  - Francis P. Lee, Tallahassee, Florida, to R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, July 11, 1846., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:64)
    Thanks him for help in managing his affairs; will try to get Camden Bank to take depreciated stock at par value; is planning to attend a general convention in 1841; rents from Mrs. Lee's New Jersey farms to be paid to R. W. Howell; his church is growing.
  - Rich[ard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, to Thomas Struthers, September 5, 1840., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 1:65)
    Discusses sale of McKean County [Pennsylvania] lands.
  - Charles C. Gaskell, Rose Cottage, to Richard W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, September 19, 1840., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:66)
    Discusses sale of [McKean County, Pennsylvania] land for the Coopers.
  - T[homas] Struthers, New York, to Rich[ar]d W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, September 27, 1840., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:67)
    Discusses purchase of B. B. Cooper lands in McKean County [Pennsylvania].
  - Terms for purchase of Benjamin B. Cooper lands by Thomas Struthers and Wm. P. Wilcox, October 1, 1840., 3 pages. D. Cop. (Box-folder 1:68)
  - Tho[ma]s B. Lee, New Orleans, to [Francis P. Lee], February 5, 1840., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:69)
    Has met the Diocese Bishop and asked if Francis P. Lee could have a church in New Orleans.
  - Francis P. Lee, [Tallahassee, Florida], to R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, April 8, 1841., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:70)
    Asks what actions Howell has taken for him; his congregation flourishing and his salary raised.
  - Rich[ard] W. Howell, Camden, to Francis P. Lee, Tallahassee, Florida, May 25, 1841., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:71)
    Purchasers of the McKean [County, Pennsylvania] lands have paid no more money; discusses some of Lee's legal problems.
  - Charles C. Gaskell, Rose Cottage, to Francis P. Lee, Tallahassee, Florida, May 28, 1841., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:72)
    Paid R. W. Howell $900 on Francis P. Lee's account; will send a list of Sarah Ann's property.
  - Henry H. Seabrook, [Key Port, New Jersey] to Francis P. Lee, Tallahassee, Florida, 1841., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:72a)
    Discusses legal matters.
  - Court petition signed by Ralph V. M. Cooper, June 16, 1841., 2 items. DS. (Box-folder 1:73)
    Lists his creditors.
  - (Box-folder 1:)
  - Francis P. Lee, Augusta, Georgia, to R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, July 3, 1841., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:74)
    Daughter Fanny died; approves business arrangements made by Howell.
  - Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, to R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, July 21, 1841., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:75)
    Mrs. Lee to visit Camden; asks Howell to provide her with $400-$500.
  - Bennington J. Randolph, Freehold [New Jersey], to Rich[ar]d A. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, August 3, 1841; September 28, 1841., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:76)
    Receipts for payments for W[illia]m Morris Cooper's share of expenses.
  - Statement by the creditors in the case of R[alph] V. M. Cooper v. his creditors, August 24, 1841., 1 page. D. (Box-folder 1:77)
  - Testimony in regard to a bond in case of R[alph] V. M. Cooper v. his creditors, August 26, 1841., 2 pages. D. (Box-folder 1:78)
  - Questions by creditors' lawyer with answers by court in case of R[alph] V. M. Cooper v. his creditors, August 26, 1841., 1 page. D. (Box-folder 1:79)
  - Statement in case of Ralph V. M. Cooper v. his creditors, August 26, 1841., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 1:80)
  - Case of Camden Bank v. Francis P. Lee and wife, September 7, 1841., 1 page. D. (Box-folder 1:81)
    Lists damages confessed.
  - Richard W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, to [Francis P. Lee], November, 1841., 5 pages. LS. (Box-folder 1:82)
    Discusses problems with land sale.
  - Francis P. Lee, Tallahassee, Florida, to Richard W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, December 11, 1841., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:83)
    Has gotten the necessary signatures for the deed arranged; thanks him for his help.
  - J[ohn] Cross, N[ew] Bruns[wic]k, to R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, December 28, 1841., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:84)
    Would like to purchase the Lee property; Morris is doing well.
  - Deed, Francis P. Lee and Sarah Ann Lee to Henry Schweitzer, et al., for land in McKean County, Pennsylvania, 1842., 5 pages. D. Cop. (Box-folder 1:85)
  - Court clerk's entries to make transfer of F[rancis] P. Lee and Sarah Ann Lee land, February 28, 1842., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 1:86)
  - S[arah] A[nn] C[ooper] Lee, Camden, South Carolina, to Richard W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, June 9, 1842., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:87)
    Has signed the deed to the McKean [County, Pennsylvania] land; asks that various debts be paid off; wants to sell other land.
  - [Sarah C. Lee], Camden, South Carolina, to [Richard W.] Howell ,July 29, 1842., 1 page. AL. (Box-folder 1:88)
    Cannot get the deed executed.
  - S[unday] S[chool] Report, July 1842., 2 pages. D. (Box-folder 1:88a)
  - Ralph V. M. Cooper, Philadelphia, to "Sister," Mrs. Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, August 3, 1842., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:89)
    His child died; he is doing well; family news; Morris inclined to be a farmer.
  - Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, to Richard W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, October 26, 1842., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 1:90)
    Trying to get legal documents required by Howell; a son was born two months ago; is living with his mother.
  - Duplicate receipts for payment of money, F[rancis] P. Lee to Moses Wright, November 25, 1842., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 1:91)
  - R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, to F[rancis] P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, January 24, 1843., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:92)
    Discusses the state of Lee's legal problems.
  - Receipts for payments on promissory note between Ralph V. M. Cooper and Wright and brother, May 20, 1843; October 2, 1845; November 3, 1845; December 24, 1846., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 1:93)
    Being paid by Francis P. Lee and Sarah C. Lee.
  - Charles Gaskell, Rose Cottage, to Sarah Ann C[ooper] Lee, Camden, South Carolina, May 24, 1843., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:94)
    Has had trouble collecting money on land sale [McKean County, Pennsylvania]; sympathy on death of her child.
  - Richard Howell, Camden [New Jersey], to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, June 17, 1843., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:95)
    Reports on Lee's New Jersey property.
  - Richard Howell, Camden, New Jersey to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, November 13, 1843., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 1:96)
    Morris left and Richard W. Howell will give him no more money.
  - Bill of sale for a slave in South Carolina, January 8, 1844., 1 page. ADS. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Francis P. Lee, Charleston, South Carolina, to [Sarah C. Lee], [February 23?, 1844]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:1a)
    Attending a convention; President Barnwell offered a resolution that delegates not be instructed; spoke at St. Michaels Church; preached at St. Phillips; met Gen. Whitefield; read prayers at St. Stephens; went back to the convention and heard arguments by Gov. Richardson and Barnwell.
  - Francis P. Lee, Charleston, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, February 25, 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:2)
    Describes the church convention he has been attending.
  - Francis P. Lee, Cheraw, to Sarah C. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, [October 18, 1844]., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:3)
    Just arrived at Cheraw; will be in Camden Tuesday.
  - Francis P. Lee, Cheraw, South Carolina, to Sarah Lee, Camden, South Carolina, October 19, 1844., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Francis P. Lee, Cheraw, South Carolina, to R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, December 21, 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:5)
    On "Cumberland" land deals.
  - W[alter] F[arquahar] Hook, Vicarage, Leeds, [England], to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, December 23, 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:6)
    Cannot provide information on order of odd fellows, has only joined it as a means of coming into contact with the lower classes.
  - E. Groom, Lake Lafayette, [Florida], to Sarah Lee, Camden, South Carolina, December 24, 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:7)
    Has been unwell; has been travelling; neighborhood news.
  - "The Carrier of the Camden [South Carolina] Journal to his friends," December 25, 1844., 3 pages. Poem. (Box-folder 2:7a)
  - R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, January 7, 1845., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:8)
    Has been trying to sell land; Morris will try farming.
  - Charles C. Gaskell, Rose Cottage, to F[rancis] P. Lee and S[arah] A[nn] C[ooper] Lee, Camden, South Carolina, March 11, 1845., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:9)
    Tells of land deals on the McKean [County, Pennsylvania] land.
  - [Sarah Ann Cooper Lee], Camden, South Carolina, to [Richard W.] Howell ,June 5, 1845., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:10)
    Asks him to check prices of carriages.
    (On same leaf as Francis P. Lee to Howell, June 6, 1845.)
  - F[rancis] P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, to Richard W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, June 6, 1845., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:10)
    Asks him to check on carriages; inquires about business matters; his brother Ben has been admitted to the bar in New Orleans.
    (On same leaf as Sarah Lee to Howell, June 5, 1845.)
  - R[ichard] W. Howell, Camden, New Jersey, to Francis P. Lee, Camden, South Carolina, August 9, 1845., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:11)
    Sends prices for carriages; discusses family land deals.